<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Visualization on Lucas Caldas</title>
    <link>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/tags/data-visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Visualization on Lucas Caldas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/tags/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project X -  Superstore Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-10/</guid>
      <description>In this project we&amp;rsquo;ll use streamlit for dashboard. For Machine Learning we can make use of regression to target continuous Profit values or classification on bolean Profitable values.
 key features: Dashboard, EDA, Supervised Learning  The Dashboard is available at: [Link]
Complete code is available at: LinkObjectives:  EDA Dashboard Classification Problem  Target Feature: profit &amp;amp; profited
Used Algorithims  Logistic Regression Knn RandomTreeClassifier  Phases:  Data Preparation Data Analysis Machine Learning Algorithm Dashboard Creation  Data Preparation Head, info, desc, null values, etc&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project IX -  Wine Classification</title>
      <link>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>Datasets consists of red variants of the Portuguese &amp;ldquo;Vinho Verde&amp;rdquo; wine. Given the nature of the dataset we can make both classification and regression tasks. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to cluster the wine variants and predict wine quality
Complete code is available at: Link key features: EDA, Clustering, Supervised Learning, Unsupervised Learning  Objectives:  EDA Wine Quality Prediction Wine Variants Clusterization  Target Feature: quality
Phases:  Data Preparation Data Analysis Supervised Learning Unsupervised Learning  Data Preparation Head, info, desc, null values, etc&amp;hellip; This df have no null values, all numerical, the dream dataset (cry emote)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project V: Customer Personality Analysis</title>
      <link>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This project will use a dataset with a company’s ideal customers attributes. The dataset consists of the costumers basics information, including ID, birth year, education, marriage status and income. In this project my interest is try to understand the costumer profile and analyze their behavior. Being capable of clustering costumers by their interests is great to make products based on their expectations, allowing a further analysis on product mix. Considering that, i&amp;rsquo;ll cluster costumers based on their similarities and them show what to focus based on each cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project II: Amazon Bestselling Books</title>
      <link>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>In this project we&amp;rsquo;ll use an amazon dataset with the top bestselling books from 2009 to 2019. The dataset consists of book&amp;rsquo;s name and author, along with user rating, number of reviews, price, release year and genre. In this project i&amp;rsquo;ll be looking for correlations between books&amp;rsquo; features.
Complete code is available at: Link key features: EDA, Data Visualization, Seaborn  Objectives:  EDA Analyse for correlation between book features  Steps:  Data Preparation Data Analysis and Vizualization  Data Preparation Dataframe without NaN values, outliers or inconsistent data, we can go directly to the Analysis Phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Netflix IMDB Scores</title>
      <link>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucastere10.github.io/portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>In this project we&amp;rsquo;ll use a database with multiples original titles from Netflix. Our main objective here is to verifiy relations between the titles characteristics and its score at IMDB. It will be a simple project composed of few steps Será um projeto simples composto por poucas etapas.
Complete code is available at: Link key features: EDA, Data Visualization, Matplotlib, Seaborn  Objetivos:  Define genre a language popularity Most watched languages Runtime-Score Ratio Verify correlations between genre and other characteristics  Etapas:  Data Preparation Data Analysis Gráficos &amp;amp; Resultados      Data Preparation The first step is to verify the integrity and characteristics of the database we are working on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
